Alex Poshivailo

(602) 810-6489 | oleg.poshiv@gmail.com | Tempe, AZ 85283

https://github.com/olegaposh | https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexposhivailo | https://www.alexposhivailo.com

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Web Developer leveraging 10+ years of experience in banking, mortgages, and investments. Earned a Bachelor's degree in Computer Information Systems and Management and recently completed an intensive 6-month full-stack web development program at the University of Arizona. Recognized for a keen eye for aesthetics and attention to detail. An excellent interpersonal communicator and collaborator that works well on team-based projects as well as independently. Known for excellent complex problem-solving and adapting well to changes.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript | React | Node.JS | Express | MySQL | MongoDB | Bootstrap | Git | Jquery | Handlebars

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

My Cost Tracker | https://my-cost-tracker.herokuapp.com/login | https://github.com/olegaposh/my_cost_tracker

- **Description:** A cost tracker that keeps records of your daily costs.
- **Role:** Oversaw the project. Designed the login using Passport.js, utilized Bcrypt to hash the user passwords, deployed MySQL to Heroku, set up the server routes, and used Handlebars and Jquery to render the front-end.
- **Technology:** HTML, CSS, MySQL, Sequelize, Express, Node.JS, Bcrypt, Handlebars, Passport.js, Jquery, Bootstrap

Cinema Spirits | https://olegaposh.github.io/Cinema_Spirits | https://github.com/olegaposh/Cinema_Spirits

- **Description:** An application that recommends drinks and movies utilizing a spirit in the user's pantry.
- **Role:** Coordinated the project, enhanced the aesthetics using CSS, set up the Drink and Movie APIs, added AOS for effects, and made the website dynamic using Jquery.
- Technology: HTML, CSS, Jquery, AOS, TheCocktailDB API, OMDb API

Offline/Online Budget Tracker | https://offline-budget-tracker123.herokuapp.com | https://git.io/JJGsu

- **Description:** Progressive Web Application that provides a seamless offline user experience that stores user transactions offline using IndexedDB and syncs the data to MongoDB as soon as there is an internet connection.
- **Role:** Implemented the routes, set up the MongoDB and IndexedDB, and made the website progressive web app compliant by setting up the web manifest and service-worker. Can be downloaded as an App on your phone.
- Technology: HTML, CSS, Node.JS, Express, Javascript, MongoDB, IndexedDB, PWA, Heroku, Compression

EXPERIENCE

The Vanguard Group, Inc., Scottsdale, AZ Fund Access Associate (2017 - Present)

2014 - Present

Process booking of incoming shares, deliver shares to contra firms, share class conversions, and trade corrections. Utilized various financial systems such as WAVE, Beta, Vast, Surpass, and AWD.

• Reduced costs 15% by collaborating with a cross-functional team to implement process improvements.

Investment Specialist (2014 - 2017)

Serviced clients over the phone by processing transactions, resolving issues, and discussing investment options.

- Decreased client errors 32% by leading a project to simplify a new account application form.
- Obtained Series 7 & 63 broker licenses.

JP Morgan Chase Bank N.A., Phoenix, AZ Mortgage Advisor

2012 - 2013

Determined eligibility and answered questions for financing mortgages and home equity products. Coached new and existing employees and took on additional managerial tasks.

• Achieved 100% quality assurance scores and ranked #1 year-over-year by exceeding performance standards.

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Web Development Certificate: University of Arizona, Mesa, AZ

Bachelor of Science in Computer Information Systems: Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ

Bachelor of Science in Management: Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ

Certificate of International Business: Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ